<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>



<chapter id="introduction">
    <?dbhtml filename="introduction.html"?>
    <chapterinfo>
        <keywordset>
           
                <keyword>JBoss Developer Studio</keyword>
                <keyword>Eclipse</keyword>
                <keyword>JBoss</keyword>
                <keyword>JBoss Tools</keyword>
                <keyword>Maven</keyword>
                <keyword>Seam</keyword>
           
        </keywordset>
        
    </chapterinfo>
      
    
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <section>
        <title>What Maven is</title>
        <para>Maven is a flexible project management, build and deployment tool from Apache Foundation. Maven uses Project Object Model to describe a project and consist from the core, plugins and repository, which can be local or remote.</para>
            <figure>
                <title>Maven Component structure</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/introduction/maven_component_structure.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
        <para>The core basing on pom.xml controls a process of calling plugins. Plugins contain all other functionality which Maven provides for  the projects: compile, build, deploy and etc.        </para>
        <para>Repository is a common place for all plugins which Maven globally uses. Local repository collects  plugins snapshots downloaded from remote repository or from a set of repositories.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>JBoss Maven Integration Functionality Overview</title>
        <para>In the beginning, we propose you to look through the table of main features of JBoss Maven Tools Integration Tools: </para>
        <table>
            <title>Key Functionality for Maven Integration Tool</title>
            <tgroup cols="3">
                <colspec colnum="1" align="left" colwidth="2*"/>
                <colspec colnum="2" colwidth="4*"/>
                <colspec colnum="3" align="left" colwidth="2*"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry>Feature</entry>
                        <entry>Benefit</entry>
                        <entry>Chapter</entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                
                
                <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry><para>Library provider</para></entry>
                    <entry><para>Maven Integration Tool provide possibility to use in Eclipse libraries, which is pointed in dependencies pom.xml section, not adding them into the project Build Path.</para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry><para>Library provider chapter</para></entry>
                </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry><para>Server deployment </para>                       </entry>
                        <entry>Server deployment is supported by Maven Integration Tools. With it you can deploy a project to the server by default Eclipse instruments.
                        </entry>
                        <entry>Deploy to the JBoss Server chapter
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>JBoss Maven Integration Facet
                        </entry>
                        <entry>The facet gives possibility to mavenizing any Dynamic Web Project.
                        </entry>
                        <entry>Mavenizing Dynamic Web Project chapter.
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                
                
                
            </tbody>
            </tgroup>
            
            
            
        </table>
        <para>Starting from 3.1 M2 version JBoss Tools  includes new JBoss Maven Integration plug-in which for now allows to create mavenized Seam projects and enable Seam tools support for imported Maven projects.</para>
        
         
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Requirements and Installation</title>
        <para>The JBoss Maven Integration requires m2eclipse to be installed.</para>
        <note>
            <title>Note:</title>
            <para>For M2 release of <property>JBoss Tools</property> it is important to use m2eclipse
                <ulink url="http://m2eclipse.sonatype.org/update/">stable update site</ulink> or the
                <ulink url="http://m2eclipse.sonatype.org/releases/0.9.9.200906081351">latest
                    integration build</ulink> that M2 was developed against. If you want to use the
                latest development release of m2eclipse you need to use the <ulink
                    url="http://download.jboss.org/jbosstools/updates/nightly/trunk/">nightly
                    builds</ulink> of <property>JBoss Tools</property>.</para>
        </note> 
        </section>
    <section>
        <title>Other relevant resources on the topic:</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para><ulink url="http://maven.apache.org/">maven.apache.org</ulink> is a official Apache Maven website.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><ulink url="http://m2eclipse.sonatype.org/">m2eclipse.sonatype.org</ulink> is a official m2eclipse (Maven Support plugin for Eclipse) website. </para>
            </listitem>
            
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    
</chapter>
